Mama?
Well, your father always picks you up, right?
Daikichi isn't my father.
My father is Grandpa.
That's weird!
Everyone has a mother and father.
So what's Daikichi?
I don't know...
What's that?!
Rin-chan always says strange stuff!
Men can't have babies!
Shut up!
You don't need a dad!
Dummies!
It takes one to know one.
Dummy, dummy, dummy!
Hiro-sensei!
Let's go!
Kouki-kun called me a dummy!
Kouki-kun kept saying dummy!
Hiro-sensei!
Kouki-kun, do you just live with your mother?
My dad went off somewhere, and then they got a divorce.
What's a "divorce"?
It's quitting marriage!
Maybe my mother is gone because she got a divorce...
I dunno.
If you don't wear your hat, they'll get mad at you.
What?
Your string is stretched out.
Rin-chan! You're getting picked up!
Rin-chan!
It's Daikichi!
He's here to pick you up!
Rin-tan, pibbup!
Maa-kun, it's okay!
Thank you.
See you tomorrow, Rin-chan.
Goodbye!
What do you feel like having for dinner?
Um, let's see...
Kouki-kun!
Your mother's here to pick you up!
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
Your mother's beautiful, you know?
At home, she's a noisy old woman!
U-Um...
Apparently, Rin always looks after Kouki...
R-Really?
My son can be a little abrasive, so he's had trouble making friends...
Thank you so much.
Oh, no! Not at all...
I-I should be thanking you...
My Rin is incredibly unsociable...
Maybe it's like birds of a feather flock together, huh?
Daikichi! You were just talking about me, weren't you?!
I wasn't saying anything bad.
Now walk fast.
I don't want you to demand that I carry you half the way again...
I won't say that!
Let's go!
Is Rin-chan Daddy's girl?
Oh, I'm not her father.
I'm more like a relative, or...
I-I'm sorry, what was I thinking?!
N-Not at all!
Mom, you're too slow!
It's nice that you made a friend, huh?
Yep!
Kouki-san said he doesn't have a father.
He said his father went somewhere after the divorce.
Rin... You know what divorce is?
Yeah. When marriage is finished, right?
Yeah, more or less...
If God finds out, He punishes the people, doesn't he?
Mmm...
I wonder if my mom is gone because of divorce, too...
Do you want to meet her?
I don't know.
I see.
But you know...
If she's like Kouki-kun's mother, I think I want to meet her!
Me too! Me too!
What?!
Rin-chan's mother is...?!
Yeah. Grandpa's maid is probably Rin's mother.
I don't believe it...
Have you heard anything about the maid?
from 19 o'clock
January 25th (Friday)
This was pretty cool.
from 19 o'clock
January 25th (Friday)
A farewell party? For me?
I'm sorry it's taken so long.
Winter clothing orders have finally settled down, so...
Thanks.
But I just can't go out at night.
My girl's six, see...
Are you telling me you haven't gone out drinking once since...?
Yeah. I just can't get out.
And I don't even care about drinking and that stuff anymore.
Maybe it's my age...
But you're only 30...
Anyway, the people in my shipping department are young,
but a lot of them have kids.
So it isn't customary to go out drinking...
Right?
You got that right.
I gotta pick up the kid at nursery school, anyway.
We had two kids in two years and the younger is 3 months old,
so if I don't get home quick, my wife...
Turns into "Wifezilla," right?
When she gets mad, she's one scary monster...
Kawachi-kun!
Gotou-san!
I heard about the farewell party!
Yeah, but I can't go out at night, so...
But they went to the trouble of arranging it,
so how about bringing the kid along?
I'll bring mine, too!
Is this your way of saying that you want to go out drinking once in a while?
Anyway, it'll be fine! Right?
I'm looking forward to it!
Coming, coming...
Daikichi, the phone.
Thanks.
Hello?
Daikichi? It seems Grandpa had a regular maid, sent from an agency...
Whoa, whoa, wait a second...
So, do you know her name?
Yoshii Masako-san, spelled with the kanji for "correct" and "child".
That's the name that's on the Maternal and Child Health Handbook, isn't it?
I believe so...
Do you intend to contact her?!
She abandoned that precious child...
Calm down a little!
You saw the Maternal and Child Health Handbook, right?
There's a lot written in there...
There's still so much we don't know, so...
Excuse me!
What I'm saying is...
I no longer know the difference between work and home...
Pardon me for being late...
You're late! Here, have a seat!
Get away from me, you drunk!
Rin-chan?! You came?!
Thank you!
You're adorable!
Eat all you want!
Here you go.
I'm glad you're here, Rin-chan.
Thank you!
Here you are, Rin-chan.
Is orange juice okay?
Mm-hm!
Rin-chan is a beauty, isn't she?
Yep, she sure is a beauty!
She's embarrassed!
Yuu-kun, I'll gather it together for you.
Rin-chan, thank you!
Kawachi-san, please, drink some more!
Rin might sleep on the way home, so...
Rin, I'm going to the washroom.
Say "bathroom"!
Yeah, yeah, I'm going to the bathroom.
He left our section high and dry.
A person shouldn't produce results, then bail!
Quitting like that is dishonest!
Sales haven't come easy this month...
Even if we do a decent job selling,
management won't look at anything but last year's results!
What are we gonna do?
How unfortunate...
The old me would've stormed in and read them the riot act, but...
I'm about to spring a leak...
Girls are so soft!
I wanna make you my kid!
My sense of importance has changed.
Kawachi-san...
About your transfer...
After seeing Rin-chan, I've come around.
Yeah, right?!
Mama! Mama!
I want to hold her forever!
Pick me up, too!
Gotou-san, Rin-chan doesn't wanna be held!
Masako-san...
What did you think about your child... about Rin?
Yuu-kun was really cute, wasn't he?
You sure do love little kids, huh?
Yep! The mail came.
Thanks.
Says this is an elementary school admission information session.
I didn't even do anything and this came...
What's wrong?
There's an admissions test, isn't there?
No, no!
You can get in without taking any test!
Really?
For sure, for sure!
Compulsory education is amazing!
Drunk!
Shoot! How's this?!
Rin-chan, he's here!
P-Pardon me...
Tch! Everyone else already left!
Sorry...
Kouki-kun, your mother's here!
Sorry, Kouki...
H-Hello.
It's been... a while.
Daikichi, are we gonna make it in time?
I'll grab a taxi!
Sorry!
The childrens' name tags can be turned around,
and they will be on the way home from school, so their names aren't visible.
Additionally, tell your child not to go to a park alone, for example,
and even if they see an adult that they know, not to go off with that person.
It's tough, isn't it?
Instead of telling them to trust people,
we have to teach them to be suspicious.
Yeah...
That one sheet we were given...
Whoops...
I'll carry them! I've got them!
How do you know what vaccinations were given up till now?
S-Sorry.
Seems like I just asked an outlandish question...
Not at all...
Do you have Rin-chan's Maternal and Child Health Handbook?
Yes, at home...
Mother-Child Health Record Book
It's got a vaccination record page.
So it's okay.
I see...
I really don't know anything...
See, I just met Rin for the first time about three months ago...
Three months?
Yeah...
That's a surprise.
I get the feeling that Rin-chan implicitly trusts you, Daikichi-san...
I'm not sure about that...
At home, she talks back a lot and she's a nag...
That's proof that she trusts you.
It's obvious you're a family.
Family...
R-Really?
That's right!
Maybe...
What?
I just jumped over your shadow!
I'm not tired!
That's okay.
Put me down!
Put me down, I said!
Thanks.
She's got almost everything on the list.
School satchel?
No, I haven't gotten that...
Well, you'd better!
By now, all the designer label and fashionable ones are sold out!
A normal one is fine.
She's a girl, so that won't do!
Fine, I'll look this weekend.
Dai-chan, are you really going to raise Rin-chan?
After all, you transferred to another section, right?
I haven't really thought that far ahead...
Mama!
Now I'll do your hair!
Okay!
You two are close, huh?
Mothers and daughters are like friends.
Come to think of it, Mom and Kazumi are like buddies, too...
Who's to say that Masako-san's situation hasn't changed
and now she wants to live with her daughter?
Look at how many shots she's had...
Her mother must have...
Souichi's Will
Boing!
A will!
"Boing"?
"If Masako found it, she would probably get rid of it.
Thus, I've taken this... roundabout method.
However, I don't really know the proper way to write a secret... riddle?
And this keyboard thing is making a fool of me,
so I can't proceed at more than a snail's pace."
Even so, these kanji conversion mistakes are dreadful!
"Already, this feeble-minded old fool's energy is exhausted.
Therefore, I'm giving up on this blog..."
That's giving up too soon!
What happened to the "greatest generation"?!
"To be continued in Rin's mother-child health record book..."
Sorry, Rin...
Let me have a look-see here...
Based on my prediction
that the person who found this piece of paper thinks warmly of Rin,
I shall give an account here of Rin and her mother, Masako.
Masako is easily misunderstood,
so I would like to start by saying that she is by no means a bad girl.
She says that she's a failure as a mother.
That she feels sorry for Rin.
Even now, she persists in being my maid.
And I believe that she will continue to do so.
I think of that as Rin's greatest happiness.
Happy? What's he mean?
She is living a vigilant life, carefully leaving no traces of herself behind,
so that if something happens to me, her existence will be hidden from all of my relatives.
Masako certainly has a mother's love for Rin.
But she's still young and may not yet have the maturity to be a parent...
I don't really understand it...
But the one thing that's clear is that he cared about Rin and her mother.
Yoshii Masako
Daikichi!
W-What?!
Listen!
I want you to make my hair look like rabbit ears!
Hah?
Like Reina-chan's mom did before!
I can't!
Do it!
There's no way I can do it! It's impossible!
Do it, I said!
Because...
she said I wasn't cute!
Huh?
Someone told you that?
Mii-chan said I wasn't cute at all!
Huh?
I think Rin wins hands down...
I want to be cute, too...
All right, all right...
She's already grown to be a fine girl
and that means her feelings can definitely be hurt...
Masako-san, did you know?
Rin's mind has already developed a lot.
She's mature in some ways, but not in others.
That's why an adult has to keep an eye on her.
Fin...ished!
This is...
Twinkle, twinkle, little star...
H-Hey, Rin...
How I wonder what you...
What are you doing?
It's a secret, so I can't tell anyone at home about Parents' Day!
Hah? Parents' Day?
So you can't look!
S-She's gonna do it with that hairstyle?
Twinkle, twinkle, little star,
How I wonder what you are.
Yoshii Masako
If you left Rin alone,
thinking she'd eventually forget even something as painful as that...
Up above the world so high,
Like a diamond in the sky.
I have no misgivings about hating you.
I want you to at least have had a good reason,
Twinkle, twinkle, little star,
but...
How I wonder what you are.
what could be a good reason for abandoning a child?
Study desk
Study chair
This is cute!
It's cute, but...
Still, you're going to be using it for a long time, so we want something more...
Oh, I know!
A desk for a young lady would be better, don't you think?
Young lady?
Yeah! One that's for a young lady would be good!
Yes!
You're sitting there again?
Do I look like a young lady?
Yeah. And I think you could still use the desk
even when you're a high school student.
Is a high school student an adult?
I guess half an adult...
Listen to me read!
"A girl went alone into a forest to play.
She lost her way and looked for the path to get back home,
but she just couldn't find it.
Suddenly, before she knew it, she came upon a tiny house in the forest."
Is this Yoshii-san?
Yes...
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
This is cute, isn't it?
Again?! Rin!
Rin!
Hey!
Daikichi...
I told you not to run off on your own like that!
Okay...
What's that?
It can make me into a young lady!
Forget it!
This is for much later!
Why?
It's sudden, so I'll show you some faces.
Angry face.
Bored face.
Embarrased face.
Good afternoon, Rin here.
Daikichi is going out to have fun.
But will he end up going out alone?
It was so important to him
that he would even let me stay home alone.
Episode 5
Daikichi Should Stay Daikichi
The next story is "Daikichi Should Stay Daikichi."
"More" face.